Stephen Crane Collection
Stephen Crane Collection
1871-1980
Crane, Stephen, 1871-1900.
19.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American novelist, journalist, poet, war correspondent. Collection includes correspondence, writings, and memorabilia of the American author and his wife, Cora Crane, and includes the research materials from a number of literary scholars and private collectors. The Stephen Crane Collection Photographs and the Lillian Gilkes Papers unrelated to Crane are inventoried and housed separately. In addition, many published Crane works and reference materials are located in Special Collections.
148913
Biographical History
Stephen Crane (1871-1900) was an American novelist, poet and journalist. Crane's mother, Mary Helen Peck, was the daughter of George Peck, an American Methodist Episcopal clergyman, author, and President of Cazenovia Seminary in Madison County, New York. Crane attended but did not graduate from Lafayette College and Syracuse University before moving to New York City where he worked as a freelance journalist and writer. His first novel, Maggie: A Girl of the Streets, was published in 1893, followed in 1895 by the novel for which he is best known, The Red Badge of Courage. The latter, about a young soldier's initiation into the horrors and ironies of war set during the American Civil War, won great acclaim for its vividness and psychological depth.
Crane and Cora Stewart-Taylor, who would become his wife, moved to Sussex, England in 1897. The two worked together as war correspondents during the Greco-Turkish War of 1897, novelized in Crane's Active Service (1899) whose central character is a journalist covering the war. Crane died at age 28 of tuberculosis in Badenweiler, Baden, Germany.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Stephen Crane Collection comprises correspondence, writings, and memorabilia of the American author and his wife, Cora Crane, as well as the research materials of a number of literary scholars and private collectors. There are also a few recordings of indeterminate provenance.
Spanning the years 1889 to 1910, Correspondence is divided into incoming and outgoing Stephen Crane letters, incoming and outgoing Cora Crane letters, and third-party correspondence, and further delineated by sender or recipient; citation numbers in parentheses (e.g., "no. 123") refer to letters in The Correspondence of Stephen Crane, Wertheim and Sorrentino, ed. (Columbia University Press, 1988). Stephen Crane's correspondence encompasses family members (Edmund and William Crane); friends (Armistead Borland, Lucius L. Button, Nellie Crouse, Clara and Moreton Frewen, Louis Senger, Post Wheeler); and publishers and literary agents (Copeland and Day, James B. Pinker, Paul Revere Reynolds). Cora Crane's correspondence consists primarily of letters she wrote for Crane to literary agent James B. Pinker and several letters to Crane's friends (Mr. and Mrs. Frewen, Corwin Knapp Linson, Louis Senger) after his death. Third-Party correspondence refers to Stephen Crane or his work.
Writings (Box 5) includes thirteen holograph manuscripts, five typescripts, and two published versions of Crane's prose and verse.
Memorabilia (Box 6) comprises family papers, legal materials, and miscellany, and includes writings by Stephen Crane's sister, Agnes, Crane's death certificate, an affidavit of M. Helen Crane, autograph albums with Crane inscriptions, and artifacts (a baseball used by Crane, calling cards, and stationery sheets with Crane's name among those on the letterhead).
In addition, the Stephen Crane Collection includes the research files of eight Crane authors and/or collectors:
The Lillian Gilkes Research Files (Boxes 7-10) comprises correspondence-subject files, writings, and memorabilia. Author of Cora Crane: a Biography of Mrs. Stephen Crane, Gilkes amassed files which contain correspondence with the Crane and Howorth families and their contemporaries, publishers, editors, and other literary scholars and researchers, as well as copies of Cora and Stephen Crane's correspondence, writings, legal papers and drawings. Writings consist of articles, book reviews, books, and miscellaneous notes by Gilkes on Cora and/or Stephen Crane. Memorabilia include photographs, printed material, writings by others, and miscellany (a brass button, and Cora Crane's calling cards).
The Cyrus Day Research Files (Box 11) contains correspondence, writings, and memorabilia concerning the 1897 shipwreck of the Commodore, on which Crane was bound for Cuba.
The Mansfield J. French Research Files (Box 11) and the Frank W. Noxon Research Files (Box 11) consist of correspondence and reminiscences about Crane by his former Syracuse University classmates.
The Vincent Starrett Research Files (Box 11) are composed of the author's correspondence with Crane's contemporaries and publishers, as well as others associated with Crane.
Corwin Knapp Linson Writings (Box 12) comprises several manuscript versions of the American artist's book about his friend, My Stephen Crane. (Linson's photographs of Crane are among the Stephen Crane Collection Photographs which is arranged and stored separately.)
Constituting the bulk of the collection, the Melvin H. Schoberlin Research Files (Boxes 13-23) encompasses correspondence-subject files, writings, and memorabilia. Correspondence-subject files comprise Schoberlin's incoming and outgoing letters of Crane's family and contemporaries and their descendants, as well as Crane scholars and researchers. Categorized as books and notes, writings include an unpublished book manuscript for a Crane biography, production records for Sullivan County Sketches and a book unrelated to Crane, and extensive research material on Crane. Clippings (relating to Crane or Schoberlin), photographs, illustrations, photostats with Crane associations, writings by others (on Crane and his work), and miscellany (Spanish moss from Cora's grave, stationery sheets with Crane's name among those on the letterhead) constitute memorabilia.
The Ames Williams Research Files (Box 24) consists of correspondence-subject files, writings, and memorabilia relating to Crane. Correspondence-subject files include Williams's incoming and outgoing letters of Stephen and Cora Crane's contemporaries and friends as well as some photocopies of their correspondence with literary agents. A paper on Crane by Williams and a copy of a photograph of one of Crane's romantic interests, Lily Brandon, complete the collection.
Recordings contains five recordings of various scholars discussing Crane, including Lillian Gilkes and Professor Walter Sutton. How these came into the collection is unknown, but they were likely part of Lillian Gilkes' research files.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence of Stephen and Cora Crane are subdivided into incoming and outgoing, and then arranged chronologically; third-party correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type and then by title. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by type.
Researcher's files are subdivided into correspondence, writings, and memorabilia, in that order; correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, while writings and memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Related Material
See also the
Stephen Crane Collection Photographs
and the
Lillian B. Gilkes Papers
(unrelated to Crane). In addition, has many published Crane works and reference materials in its Rare Books holdings; please refer to for a complete listing. is also the repository of the papers of
George Peck
, Crane's maternal grandfather.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Borland, Armistead.; Button, Lucius L.; Crane, Agnes Elizabeth, 1856-1884.; Crane, Cora, 1865 or 6-1910.; Crane, Edmund, 1886-1957; Crane, Stephen, 1871-1900.; Crane, William.; Crouse, Nellie.; Crane family.; Day, Cyrus Lawrence, 1900-1968.; DuMond, Frank Vincent, 1865-1951.; French, Mansfield Joseph, 1872-; Frewen, Clara, 1851-1935.; Frewen, Moreton, 1853-1924.; Gilkes, Lillian Barnard, 1902-; Hubbard, Elbert, 1856-1915.; Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1853-1937.; Linson, Corwin Knapp, b. 1864.; Mayfield, John S., 1904-1983.; Noxon, Frank W.; Pinker, James B.; Reynolds, Paul R. (Paul Revere), 1904-1988.; Schoberlin, Melvin H., 1912-; Senger, Louis.; Stallman, R. W. (Robert Wooster), 1911-1982.; Starrett, Vincent, 1886-1974.; Wheeler, Post, 1869-1956.; Williams, Ames W. (Ames William); Copeland and Day.; American literature -- 19th century.; American poetry -- 19th century.; Authors, American.; Authors and publishers.; Greco-Turkish War, 1897 -- Journalists.; Journalists -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Poets, American.; Spanish-American War, 1898 -- Campaigns -- Cuba -- Journalists.; War correspondents.; Articles.; Sound recordings.; Audiotapes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Illustrations.; Notes (documents); Photographs.; Poems.; Video recordings.; Videotapes.; Authors.; Journalists.; Novelists.; Poets.; War correspondents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gifts and purchases, 1950-1965.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Stephen Crane
    - Outgoing, 1889 (Box 1)
      Ap 4 Armistead Borland (no. 3)
    - Outgoing, 1890 (Box 1)
      Mr 10 Armistead Borland (no. 4)
      N? Claverack schoolmate (no. 7
    - Outgoing, 1891 (Box 1)
      Ja 9 Odell Hathaway (no. 8)
    - Outgoing, 1892 (Box 1)
      F 16 Armistead Borland (no. 10)
      D 14 Lucius L. Button (no. 13)
    - Outgoing, 1894 (Box 1)
      F 20 Lucius L. Button (no. 29)
      D 22 Post Wheeler (no. 57)
      D 22? Copeland and Day (no. 58)
      late Post Wheeler (no. 60)
      late Post Wheeler (no. 61)
      late Post Wheeler (no. 62)
    - Outgoing, 1895 (Box 1)
      Ja 2 Copeland and Day (no. 64)
      Ja 30 Louis Senger (no. 71)
      F 19 Corwin Knapp Linson (no. 76)
      Ag 3 Karl Knortz (no. 99)
      O 24 Willis Brooks Hawkins (no. 115)
      N 5 Post Wheeler (no. 124)
      N 23 Louis Senger (no. 143)
      D 10 Louis Senger (no. 150)
      D 31 Nellie Crouse (no. 166)
    - Outgoing, 1896 (Box 1)
      Ja 6 Nellie Crouse (no. 173)
      Ja 7 Louis Senger (no. 176)
      Ja 11 Louis Senger (no. 179)
      Ja 11 (4) Louis Senger (no. 180-3)
      Ja 12 Nellie Crouse (no. 184)
      Ja 26 Nellie Crouse (no. 186)
      F 5 Nellie Crouse (no. 200)
      F 11 Nellie Crouse (no. 204)
      F 15 Editor of The Critic (foldered separately)
      Mr 1 Nellie Crouse (no. 209)
      Mr 24 Dewitt Miller (no. 219)
      Mr 24 Louis Senger (no. 220)
      late Ap Viola Allen (no. 235)
      [May 1896+] Lucius L. Button (no. 242)
      My 10 Charles J. Pike (no. 243)
      Ag 3 E.S. Goodhue, M.D. (no. 262)
      N 3 Lucius L. Button (no. 281)
    - Outgoing, 1897 (Box 1)
      Ja 4 copy Lillian Barrett
      Ja 8 Charles Pope (no. 307)
      S 9 Edmund B. Crane (no. 328)
      N 8 Louis Senger (no. 336)
      D 20 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 346)
      [1897] book Louis Senger
      late 1897? Elbert Hubbard (no. 351)
    - Outgoing, 1898 (Box 2)
      Ja 31 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 360)
      F 8 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 365)
      Mr 1 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 372)
      Mr 13 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 374)
      Mr 17 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 378)
      early My Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 384)
      My 8 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 385)
      My 30 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 387)
      Je 8 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 388)
      early S Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 396)
      S 14 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 397)
      S 27 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 402)
      O 21 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 410)
      O 24 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 411)
      O 25-28? Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 412)
      N 1 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 414)
      N 24 book J.G. Widrig (no. 423)
    - Outgoing, 1899 (Box 2)
      Ja 19 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 448)
      Ja 31 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 454)
      F 1 James B. Pinker (no. 455)
      F 4 James B. Pinker (no. 457)
      F 9 James B. Pinker (no. 463)
      F 10 "Dear Sir" (no. 464)
      F 13 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 466)
      F 20 Clara Frewen (no. 471)
      F 21 James B. Pinker (no. 472)
      late F Pocket Magazine (no. 477)
      Mr 2 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 480)
      Mr 12 Moreton Frewen (no. 485)
      Mr 16 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 488)
      Mr 17 James B. Pinker (no. 490)
      Mr 25 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 493)
      Mr 30 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 498)
      Mr 31 Paul Revere Reynolds (no. 499)
      Ap 10 Moreton Frewen (no. 500)
      My 1 James B. Pinker (no. 513)
      My 15 Moreton Frewen (no. 517)
      Je 8 Camilla Ingalls (no. 524)
      Jl 21 James B. Pinker (no. 528)
      Ag 1? James B. Pinker (no. 530)
      Ag 4 James B. Pinker (no. 531)
      Ag 6? James B. Pinker (no. 533)
      Ag 10 William Howe Crane (no. 536)
      Ag 13? Henry Sanford Bennett (no. 537)
      Ag 13? James B. Pinker (no. 538)
      Ag 15? John [Scott-Stokes?] (no. 543)
      Ag 29 Henry Sanford Bennett (no. 547)
      S 10? George Wyndham (no. 554)
      S 22 James B. Pinker (no. 558)
      S 26 Moreton Frewen (no. 562)
      S 28? James B. Pinker (no. 563)
      S 30? James B. Pinker (no. 565)
      S 31 James B. Pinker (no. 568)
      O 23? James B. Pinker (no. 578)
      N 4 James B. Pinker (no. 583)
    - Outgoing, 1900 (Box 2)
      Ja 31 S. Crane's namesake (no. 636)
      F 5 James B. Pinker (no. 643)
      F 5 James B. Pinker (no. 644)
      Mr 8 James B. Pinker (no. 657)
      Mr 10 James B. Pinker (no. 658)
      Mr 24 James B. Pinker (no. 661)
      Mr 31 James B. Pinker (no. 666)
      My 23 Henry Sanford Bennett (no. 718)
    - Incoming, 1893-1896 (Box 2)
      Mr 22 1893 Barry, John D. (no. 18)
      Ap 1 1896 Black, William
      O 31 1894 Copeland and Day (no. 49)
      My 1 1895 copy Copeland and Day (no. 84)
      S 5 1899 Stokes, Frederick A. (no. 552)
      S 23 1899 Stokes, Frederick A. Stephen Crane (no. 561)
      [Ap 1896?] copy Verdi, P. (no. 239)
  - Cora Crane
    - Outgoing, 1899-1906 (Box 3)
      F 13 1899 Margery Pease (no. 468)
      Mr 6 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 482)
      Ap 25 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 508)
      Ag 31 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 548)
      S 30? 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 567)
      O 8 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 571)
      O 21 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 576)
      O 26 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 581)
      O 30 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 582)
      D 7 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 599)
      D 12 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 600)
      D 18 1899 James B. Pinker (no. 601)
      Ja 2 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 612)
      Ja 6 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 620)
      Ja 7 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 621)
      Ja 9 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 626)
      Ja 10 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 627)
      Ja 24 1900 Post Wheeler (no. 633)
      F 14 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 651)
      F 20 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 654)
      mid-Mr 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 659)
      Mr 29 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 664)
      Ap 6 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 670)
      Ap 8 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 673)
      Ap 11 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 676)
      Ap 15? 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 680)
      Ap 16 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 681)
      Ap 17 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 682)
      Ap 23 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 688)
      Ap 24 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 689)
      My 5 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 700)
      My 8? 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 706)
      My 20 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 714)
      My 23 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 719)
      My 29 1900 James B. Pinker (no. 722)
      Ag 15 1900 James B. Pinker
      Ag 28 1900 "Dear Sir"
      S 28 1900 Corwin Knapp Linson
      O 18 1900 Corwin Knapp Linson
      O? 1900 James B. Pinker
      O 22 1900 Louis Senger
      O 26 1900 G.H. Perris
      Ag 25 1904 G.H. Perris
      D 1906 The Moreton Frewens
    - Incoming, 1910 (Box 3)
      F 10 [Budd, Ernest] Edward
  - Third-party correspondence
    - Third-party correspondence, 1894-1903 (Box 4)
      Crane, William to Nellie [ ] Je 21 1900
      Dumond, Frank Vincent to Mr. Noble Ap? 1900
      Dumond, Frank Vincent to Mr. Noble Ap 12 1900
      Dumond, Frank Vincent to Mr. Noble My? 1900
      Dumond, Frank Vincent to Mr. Noble Je 10 1900
      Hubbard, Elbert to Mr. Day Ap 16 1896
      Ingalls, Camilla to Margery Pease Je 21 1900
      Linson, Corwin Knapp to Louis Senger D 4 1894
      Linson, Corwin Knapp to Louis Senger Ja 10 1895
      Linson, Corwin Knapp to Louis Senger Ja 1899
      Linson, Corwin Knapp to Louis Senger My 27 1899
      Reynolds, Paul Revere R.W.[sic] Johnson to D 22 1896
      Stokes, Frederick A. to James B. Pinker Je 6 1900
      Stokes, Frederick A. to James B. Pinker N 11 1902
      Stokes, Frederick A. to James B. Pinker Je 26 1903
      [ ] to Louis Senger D 4 1896
- Writings
  - Prose
    - "Across the Covered Pit", typescript ms. (Box 5)
    - "The Angel-child", autographed holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "A Desertion", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "A Detail", holograph draft (Box 5)
    - "An Explosion of Seven Babies", typescript ms. (Box 5)
    - "Great Bugs in Onondaga" New-York Tribune, June 1, 1891 (Box 5)
      See also "Huge Electric Light Bugs" and "The Syracuse Bugs"
    - "Greed rampant", typescript ms. (Box 5)
    - "Huge Electric Light Bugs," Syracuse, New York Standard, p. 6, June 1, 1891 (Box 5)
      See also "Great Bugs in Onondaga" and "The Syracuse Bugs"
    - "Jack", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "The King's Favor", typescript ms. (Box 5)
    - "Ol' Bennet & the Indians", autographed holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "Prologue", autographed holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "The Syracuse Bugs," New-York Daily Tribune, June 2, 1801 (Box 5)
      See also "Great Bugs in Onondaga" and "Huge Electric Light Bugs"
  - Verse
    - "I'd rather have-", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - "Lines", typescript ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "Fast rode the knight", autographed holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "I looked here / I looked there", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "In a large vaulted hall", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "In heaven, / Some little blades of grass.. .", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "Should the wide world roll away", holograph ms. (Box 5)
    - Untitled - "What? You define me God with these trinkets", holograph ms. (Box 5)
- Memorabilia
  - Family
    - Agnes Crane's diary (fragment) pp. 53-60, 1874-1875 (Box 6)
    - Agnes Crane's "Memory book ", 4/23/1875; leaf about J. Townley Crane (Box 6)
    - Agnes Crane's "The Cipher Dispatches", 1878; holograph prose ms. (Box 6)
  - Legal
    - Death certificate of Stephen Crane - "Badenweiler ", 6/11/1900 (Box 6)
    - M. Helen Crane - affidavit as executrix of J. Townley Crane's estate, Mar. 1880 (Box 6)
    - Will of Stephen Crane (copy), 1900 (Box 6)
  - Miscellany
    - Autograph albums of Armistead Borland containing Stephen Crane's inscriptions, 4/4/1889; 3/10/1890; 2 volumes (Box 6)
    - Baseball used by Crane at Geneva, N.Y. in game with Hobart College, May 23, 1891 (Box 6)
    - Calling cards (2) (Box 6)
    - Claverack Academy and Hudson River Institute, 1 illustration and advertisements (with copy photographs and negatives) (Box 6)
    - Stationery sheet with letterhead: "Crane's New Jersey Coast News Bureau, Sandy Hook to Barnegat Bay, Asbury Park, N.J., J. Townley Crane, Manager, Stephen Crane, Secretary, Edgar C. Snyder, Treasurer", 1891-1892 (Box 6)
- Lillian Gilkes research files
  - Correspondence-subject files
    - B (Box 7)
    - Barr, Philip, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Barrett, Richmond, 1934-1963 (Box 7)
    - Bassan, Maurice, 1963-1969 (Box 7)
    - Beer, Alice, 1956-1959 (Box 7)
    - Beer, Thomas, See Crane Family - from Thomas Beer files (Box 7)
    - Berryman, John, 1954-1956 (Box 7)
    - Bohnenberger, Elizabeth and Carl, 1943 (Box 7)
    - Bower, Warren, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Bowers, Fredson, 1968-1972 (Box 7)
    - Brede Place, undated (Box 7)
    - Broward, Audrey, 1954-1960 (Box 7)
    - Brown, Spencer Curtis, 1954-1959 (Box 7)
    - Budd, Louis, 1970 (Box 7)
    - C (Box 7)
    - Cady, Edwin H., 1964-1973 (Box 7)
    - Columbia University, 1954-1959 (Box 7)
    - Colvert, James, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Corcoran, Marguerite, 1955 (Box 7)
    - Cordell, Richard A., 1955-1956 (Box 7)
    - Cornell University Press, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Crane, Cora
      - Drawings, negative (Box 7)
      - Drawings, oversize (Oversize 1)
      - Frewens correspondence, 1898-1900; photocopies of letters (most from the Library of Congress) (Box 7)
      - Legal papers (Box 7)
      - Photocopies of letters, 1898-1901 (Box 7)
      - Writings, 1901 (Box 7)
    - Crane, Stephen
      - Legal papers (Box 7)
      - Photocopies of letters, 1888-1900 (Box 7)
      - Writings, photocopies of articles and clippings (Box 7)
    - Crane Family
      - [Miscellaneous], 1948-1962 (Box 7)
      - From Thomas Beer files, 1921-1934 (Box 7)
    - D (Box 7)
    - Daniel, Richard P., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Day, Cyrus L., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Dent & Sons, Ltd., 1959 (Box 7)
    - E (Box 7)
    - F (Box 7)
    - Forman, Barry, See Harold Frederic Family
    - Franchere, Hoyt C., 1958-1961 (Box 7)
    - Harold Frederic family, 1958-1961; undated (Box 7)
    - Frewen, Roger, 1955-1961 (Box 7)
    - Frewen, Roger/Kipling, Rudyard, 1900; photocopies of letters from the Library of Congress (Box 7)
    - Garner, Stanton, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Gullason, Tom, 1970 (Box 7)
    - H (Box 8)
    - Hallam, George W., 1964-1967 (Box 8)
    - Harold Frederic Edition, See Garner, Stanton
    - Hathaway, Odell S., 1961-1962 (Box 8)
    - Hicks, Granville, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Hoffman, Daniel, 1954-1960 (Box 8)
    - Hoskins, Frank L., 1964-1972 (Box 8)
    - Howorth Family (Cora Crane's family), 1954-1958 (Box 8)
    - Indiana University Press, 1959-1968 (Box 8)
    - Jones, Edith Richie, 1954 (Box 8)
    - K (Box 8)
    - Kantor, James Roland Kristofer, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Kazin, Alfred, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Keller, Dean H., 1968-1970 (Box 8)
    - King, Robert T., 1969 (Box 8)
    - Koster, Donald N., 1968-1972 (Box 8)
    - Kyles, Gillian, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - L (Box 8)
    - Leary, Lewis, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Leslie, Shane, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Levenson, Jack C., 1970 (Box 8)
    - Lohf, Kenneth A., 1969 (Box 8)
    - The London Times, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
    - McCready, Ernest W., 1934; photocopies of letters (Box 8)
    - May, Philip, 1948-1960 (Box 8)
    - Mayfield, John S., 1954-1977 (Box 8)
    - Monteiro, George, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
    - N (Box 8)
    - New York Public Library, 1955-1959 (Box 8)
    - Nottinghamshire Guardian, 1956 (Box 8)
    - O (Box 8)
    - Osborn, Scott C., 1956-1969 (Box 8)
    - Paine, Ralph D., 1954-1956 (Box 8)
    - Mark Patterson & Co. Limited, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Pease, Muriel, 1955-1961 (Box 8)
    - "Permission to Publish" letters, 1958-1959 (Box 8)
    - Powell, Anthony, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Roeder, Ralph, 1954 (Box 8)
    - S (Box 8)
    - Schoberlin, Melvin H., 1948-1961 (Box 8)
    - Sheridan, Clare, See Williams, Ames
    - Smillie, Lily Brandon Monroe (and family), 1955 (Box 8)
    - Solomon, Eric, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Stallman, Robert W., 1953-1956 (Box 8)
    - Stewart family (Cora Crane's 2nd husband), 1901; 1959 (Box 8)
    - Stronks, James, 1961-1972 (Box 8)
    - T (Box 9)
    - Turner, Arlin, 1970-1972 (Box 9)
    - U (Box 9)
    - Ward, Lynd, 1959 (Box 9)
    - Wells, Lester G., 1954-1960 (Box 9)
    - Wheeler, Harry F., 1956 (Box 9)
    - Williams, Ames, 1945-1955 (Box 9)
    - Woodward, Robert H., 1962-1970 (Box 9)
    - Y (Box 9)
  - Writings
    - Articles
      - "Egg-Walking in Biography", typescript draft (Box 9)